what we see is you know if let's say
that the insurer wants to maintain his
portfolio loss they showed 65 percent
you know 65 percent plus the IAD element
of let's say 32 percent is a combined of
97 which is let you know by global
standards reasonable combined to run a
profitable book act now if the pricing
action were not taken at all and if we
assume that medical trend is running at
10 percent you can see and if the
starting point for the insurance company
sixty percent you can actually see that
if left without any pricing action the
portfolio actually worsens to about
eighty five eighty eight percent over a
five year time frame so that's point
number one and really what I want to
illustrate through the other two lines
is the sensitivity of when you undertake
the pricing action if you undertook the
pricing action your zero looking ahead
three years and and let's say three
years is is the price revision cycle
that you're interested in then you are
alright and you are able to manage your
portfolio to the sixty five percent
target that the company let's say needs
but instead of your zero if you
implemented that in year one you're
actually going to overshoot you know the
financial target of the company by by
your two by quite a margin so that's you
know the point I want to make here is
look just as we talked about general
inflation medical inflation medical
trend is real and even if insurers have
loss ratios that appear to be attractive
timely pricing action is quite critical
to this to our job as as portfolio
managers another thing which is which is
of big you know I would say very big
importance to our country and I go back
to a book written way back in 1972 by
Victor Fuchs and he asked this question
you know who will pay for health care on
the chart on your left you
see that in most advanced countries they
spend about 8% of GDP on health care in
the United States that number is is more
than twice at 17 or percent in India we
spend about 4 percent of GDP on health
care a government is probably about 1
percent of that now the reality is that
with the Prime Minister
you know Prime Minister's ambition of 5
5 trillion as economy by 2025 with
rising incomes with you know a
burgeoning middle class you know in time
we will get to 78 percent of GDP on
healthcare and and of course with the
rising burden of disease so in time we
will start to spend you know 78 percent
of GDP on healthcare I think this is a
reality that that will play out sooner
than later
now now this poses very important
questions for us as a society and as an
industry because this increasing spend I
think we need to as a society recognize
that we need to exercise choices in
terms of how this money is spent on your
right is a table which illustrates and
when we talk about medical advancement
you know what is the difference in price
between a robotic surgery and a
laparoscopic procedure and and that
difference is actually very stark now
for that particular individual
you know the robotic surgery may indeed
result in better health health outcomes
but when you have a third-party payer
system or when you have public financing
I think as a society we need to ask some
hard questions in terms of hey is a
rupee better spent in our particular
individuals health outcome or is it
better spent in building toilets or
public health facilities or in making
sure that more and more people have
access to quality health care as opposed
to a small set having access to you know
ultra-modern most sophisticated
healthcare so I think this is a very
important societal choice that we will
need to make
as a country and this is at a micro
level a choice that we get hit with as
insurers reasonably frequently
especially as medical technology
advances because for that particular
individual
you know when exercising that choice you
know it's almost always that you want
the right thing and the best quality
care but the reality is that you know
when a claim is paid it is paid out of
pooled money and then it may not be the
best choice for all of the population
that has pulled in the money so I think
this is again something that the young
and bright students of an ia could sort
of discuss and debate and you know had
maybe helped the country shape its
opinion and how do we make some of these
choices and lastly and I think I think
one of the speaker's earlier in the day
referred to the fact that look India is
unique and indeed we are unique there is
no country except perhaps China which is
comparable in terms of how our health
care and health financing system is
evolving and perhaps the most important
structural decision which I feel we need
to make today is to solve this incentive
problem between payers and providers the
reality is that for most part the way we
pay providers today in India is more or
less mirroring what happens let me say
in the United States and you know any
economic actor responds to incentives
and today you know the more you treat
the go the more you get paid and that
system in time will not become
sustainable so I think as an industry
how do we align incentives that that
payments between finance ears of care
and people who deliver care done in a
way which is patient centric but also
better the line incentives between you
know who's paying for the money who's
getting the money what are the
treatments being you know being
performed in the best interest of the
consumer I think this is a very very
important structural question that needs
to be addressed by in the C
collaboration today because I fear that
if we did not address this today
we're going down a path which is
actually quite unsafe unsustainable in
times to come so thank you hopefully
there is some you know food for thought
for all of the you know students sitting
in the audience and I'd be delighted if
some of these actually became questions
that were delved into a little more
deeply by the students here
thank you thank you sir
the last topic for this session is
getting ready for the digital world
which will be presented by mr. Nilesh
gurgel before beginning I take great
pleasure in introducing mr. Gargan sir
is the managing director and CEO of Tata
AIG general Insurance Company Limited
having over 24 years of rich experience
in the financial sector sir has worked
with companies like ICICI Limited
Citigroup and ICICI Lombard general
insurance so there is an active member
of the CII National Committee in
insurance and also sits on the governing
bodies of many reputed organizations
like Insurance Information Bureau and NS
DC I would request further comments
mr. Srinivasan director nie my son
debugger Krishna and my esteemed panel
seniors colleagues and friends of the
insurance industry and the young
students often a good afternoon and
thank you for inviting me to be part of
this
[Music]
there's lots been you know it's been a
very very fascinating morning what's
been said about how the world is
changing
you know there's innovation disruption
technology you know the customers
thinking of new things so I think the
topic has been very well chosen
strategic perspective on building a
resilient industry I just wanted to you
know law themes you know and topics have
been spoken about one of the things
comments you know which I wanted to make
which is not related to so much about
anything but yet related to everything
is that I believe you know that the
fundamental thing which we need to focus
on is mindsets and when we are talking
about how do we build a resilient
industry basically we will be able to
build a resilient industry only if we
are able to change with the changing
needs of the customers and I think you
know Christian spoke about it first of
all the mindsets of the customers are
changing you know we all know 50 percent
of the population of India his quota is
below 25 when we look at 2025 2030 these
young minds you know these people are
going to become not already they are
going to become the bulk of the
purchasing they are gonna become the
customers of India and what I've I mean
all of us have realized you know either
like you know looking at our kids or you
know the people on the sitting in the
back benches you know on their own
behavior I think the pattern of you know
the mindset of a lot of these young
consumers is very different you know
what we call today nobody I mean I'm
here making a intelligent
gasps I think the pride which used to be
associated about 25 years back with
owning a home or owning a car or owning
a two-wheeler I don't think you know is
there anymore
nobody is very keen on purchasing and I
said an asset is looked more as a
liability then a you know an asset
everybody is very impatient so when you
are wanting you know so the I mean the
insurance agent is gonna come visit me
on Friday and then fill up a form and
then the answer will come on
two weeks later I don't think you know
this just generation you know so if they
if 6 o'clock 6 p.m. you know you felt a
need you know that I want this product
then you order it 601 and you know then
you know you get the delivery next day
morning or you know whatever so it's a
services economy consumption in bytes
you know so again the India probably
changed you know when I think some
company introduced the shampoo in a one
rupee you know sachet or the telecom
rotary charger for 10 rupees or in one
rupees I mean I think most of the people
now again I'm making intelligent guess
most of the people we know 25 are very
happy with the prepaid connections and
most of the people above 50 I would say
are over 40 are happy with post wait
connections I think that is you know
what we need to understand you know how
in the mindsets of today's customers you
know young customers are consuming
products you know wizz-wizz
subscribing to services rather than you
know ownership of products and you know
that kind of gives us a lot of clues in
terms of you know how the insurance
industry is going to change equally if
not bigger you know the challenge is
also the mindsets of the manufacturers
and you know there have been some you
know Mahadev spoke about some great
examples if I am NOT you know wrong you
know I think Oscar itself my already be
is valued at about four billion dollars
four billion dollars that's a thirty
thousand crore company which has started
by some techies you know maybe I think
you know just about three or four years
back so I mean Laura from in to put it
in perspective you know a lot of the
Indian insurance companies you know
don't have you know that
value so when I am talking about
mindsets I think you know our
traditional mindset and I'm talking
about myself I'm confessing most of us
most of the times you know we start
thinking that change you know SpaceX or
NASA it's happening somewhere in Silicon
Valley and it's happening sometime far
away but all the examples of Ahura have
said you know all of those are existing
companies which are running very viable
models or when we spoke about penguin or
Songun those are companies which are
existing right now and doing very well
in this ecosystem so I think and again
if we look back when we look back at
some of these other examples of famous
examples of Kodak or certain other
companies I'm sure they had very very
bright people super bright probably the
best but probably when you get
complement and think that we are already
doing very well see the interesting the
the fascinating part about a lot of this
change is the gist there is a certain
gestation period when you are trying to
destroy you know there was a word
disruption you know which was used
disruptive innovation is a word you know
which was coined you know about 15 years
back very interesting disruptive
innovation you know fundamentally also
means you know that you have to destroy
parts of your existing organization to
create something new and but when you
destroy something and create something
new the results of that are gonna come
after three years or you know maybe 36
months you know maybe even longer than
that you know maybe 60 months do as
management teams you know if you are
having management teams you know if you
are having 10 hours of you know limited
10 hours you know if you are working for
this quarter this year numbers or
whatever do we have the vision or the
mindset you know to make changes and
investments you know which results are
gonna come after five years or after ten
years and which is where I think the
intelligence is all there in the room I
think so to my mind I just wanted to you
know make this fundamental point it's
same very important to understand the
mindset of the customer it's very
important we change our own mindsets
maybe what was working for the last I
mean of course there's a great amount of
respect for organizations you know have
been 400 years
but maybe you know the customer is
changing what has worked for the last 10
years or 25 years might not work for the
next 25 years
and that's something you know I think
you know which is Richards the you know
I think the foundation of this entire
debate you know that how quickly can we
change our own mindsets and understand
the mindsets of the you know New Age
customer and which is our talk a little
bit about I'm not gonna not gonna you
know use any of the large big strategies
you know which Sundeep spoke about in
terms of you know Y and VY but I mean
there has been you know we all know
these numbers you know there is a very
very strong you know internet community
which is developing in India but I think
the difference you know which is
happening is you know that instead of
just Internet users now I think more and
more customers are becoming comfortable
transacting on the Internet
and that's something you know which the
change we've I mean there is whether the
search words you know whether it's the
number of Internet users I think that
changes in happening very fast and we
need to be cognizant of that change so
this is I'll just a little busy slide
you know but I mean the point you know
which I am trying to make here is you
know there is lot of the industry's
primed for digital disruption and today
there are the disruptors on one side you
know so whether the disruption is going
to come from Amazon Google the in short
X the fintechs you know there's a lot of
people who are going to you know create
the reception on the other side I think
you know there's no also enablers which
have happened today India itself you
know the kind of data ecosystem you know
that India has the kind of payment
ecosystem which India has today was
unimaginable ten years back and you know
the regulation is also kind of you know
trying to make changes or moving in pace
you know there is you know we were
talking about sandbox in the morning but
I think you know equally exciting is you
know today having these data bases you
know where you know you can maybe
real-time you know check the credit
score of a person you know you can you
should be able to I'm hoping at some
point in time in the future be able to
check real time the risk score of a
person you know what is the propensity
of or or to identify a fraud I think
these are going to be
some of the very fundamental changes so
these are all the enablers which are
happening in terms of the ecosystem
players etc so I think again you know
this we can look at it as a threat or we
can look at as an opportunity I would
say for all of us you know there is a
huge business opportunity you know
whether it's in terms of digitizing the
existing channels so I think you know a
lot of times you know we talk about an
either/or approach you know that either
the traditional channel has to die the
agents have to die or you know vis-a-vis
digital I also think you know I don't
think it has to be that way and you know
there is this company called progressive
you know in the u.s. you know which is
where your expense ratio is similar
between both digital channel and the
agency Channel so can you you know use
all the technologies all the
seamlessness of the process and hence
expense reduction for your traditional
channel and enable them to increase the
conversion rate and it use a cost so I
think you know that's a you know big
opportunity which is there you know then
of course that direct-to-consumer which
we all know and the ecosystem plays so
today there are so many ecosystems not
in us not in Germany not in China but in
India where people are having you know
one crow two crows five crores 10 crores
you know interactions with customers oh
no in a very very short timeframe there
was you know one of the there was a
Kerala floods you know when it happened
you know so one of the entities you know
started raising you know source funding
you know crowd sourcing for Kerala funds
and you know just ticket size of 10
rupees you know they were able to you
know in just one week's time you know be
able to you know collect more money for
Kerala floods you know which lot of
state governments you know provided
that's the power of I think you know
some of these platforms you know and you
know it's already there in India and you
know we need to open our imagination
into what can be how can we plug into
this and you know what can we do so I
think a little bit a few comments on you
know what are the so what do we do and I
am talking about the insurance industry
and for for me you know there are
nothing 3 very key enablers you know to
simplify things you know so one is tech
of course I mean that's the starting
point of all of this second is all
structures laugh talented and
which is where I think you know the niña
aspect you know becomes very important
third is you know the products and
ecosystems I think you know some part of
that has been spoken about on the you
know if I talked about the talent part
you know which was a very critical
aspect the only thing you know I'm very
happy you know that ni is talking about
erm program the only other thing you
know which sir I would put a request is
you know I think it's also becoming very
important today to balance the domain
traditional domain skills with the New
Age skills and when I say new their
skills you know might not have anything
to do the insurance but to bring a
powerful solution to the customer is
required you know well what I mean by
that is you know we need data architects
we need data engineers you know we need
data scientists so can we also look at
something you know wherein we are able
to equip our students you know with some
good data modeling techniques to
understand real data that's a very very
important input you know going forward
similarly you know Laura that what does
does it take you know to develop some
infuse you know these students while you
know they are getting lot of domain
knowledge you know with certain
technology technology when I say you
know its knowledge about you know
building a UI UX or maybe coding at a
basic level so I think that's again you
know so there is somebody was telling me
yesterday a financial engineering is
becoming a very important aspect I think
you know so these skill sets are also
going to be equally important for us to
I mean you know so one is you know we we
get these guys you know but I think the
most powerful combination will be if we
get somebody who wants understands you
know a fire risk or you know the rating
equation of a motor vehicle along with
that he or she also understands you know
what how do a little bit about data
modeling or you know uyu exciting that
combination is going to become very
unique in the going forward and somebody
who's at the cusp of both of these you
know those those are the resources which
shall be the most valuable you know
going forward on the tech you know
basically I mean lot of you know so
there is clearly in short X you know a
new way digital companies
you know which don't have legacy I mean
this message is you know I think more
for the all of the traditional you know
companies you know how do we you know
change and change and destroy parts of
our organization you know to become much
more agile so that our technology
architectures instead of slowing us down
so what is our readiness you know to
deliver a product in six one week's time
or you know even a one month's time you
know which ways you know or one year
time those are the hard questions you
know I think some of us you know we'll
need to ask ourselves you know vis-a-vis
our legacy systems our processes you
know to be made lean and digitized you
know real-time underwriting and claim
processing again that's happening
already you know so it's we it's not
something you know which is a real-time
claim processing is is is you know being
discussed at a conference you know which
is the future forward-looking conference
you know but those are products you know
which a lot of companies in lot of
countries including India you know are
you know trying to you know are already
you know offering and that's you know as
somebody said you know the customer has
to be the center of this conversation
and the customer wants that that's the
right answer it doesn't matter you know
what the underwriter or the insurance
company you know thinks big data and
analytics you know again lots been
spoken about then other thing is again
the mindset of what do we do with it
build versus by you know how much is in
source and how much is outsourced you
know do we look at no other in short X
as a competition or do we look at as
them as collaboration I think that's
another food for thought for all of us I
spoke about the talent you know but I
think it's also very important you know
to relook at the organizational
structures today when you look at a lot
of these you know tech startups their
organizational structures are very
different than traditional organizations
and and you know and interestingly my
interactive view of them you know the
lot of them are much more focused on the
customer you know so in terms of you
know sometimes you know the traditional
organization is built you know that's a
very manufacturer construct we have
departments and underwriting
underwriting Department frankly has no
meaning for the customer I mean we can
we can think it's the most important you
know department from our perspective so
how do we kind of
again rethink of our organizational
structure rather than just creating a
digital vertical you know which is on
the left hand side you know which is a
without making any fundamental change
but how do we make digital thought
process empowerment speed of
decision-making you know more is a part
of you know every department and you
know become like again it's a it's a
cliche in word you know become become a
digital organization so and then there
as I said earlier you know we need to
the only answer to my mind as you know
to get very good digital native and data
say we talent to create you know again
long the consultants talk about these
create these very agile squads but
basically I mean whatever whatever
jargon you know which we use I think the
idea is you know how do we create but
team which has got underwriters
technology you know marketing all of
those people together who are empowered
to take a decision so they solve a
customer problem and not that you know
that the file again goes to the boss of
the under head underwriting you know so
it's you know so they're nothing changes
you know that's a very superficial
change I think that's something you know
again I would say which is very
important to what extent can we create
company within a company you know so
that's something you know which again is
food for thought for us and can we
create the you know startup like culture
which is you know if you have to fail
you fail fast and you know again you
know we take down this thing and so
traditional companies you know like
myself you know we have got lot of
strengths but can we you know can we use
those strengths you know very powerfully
so we've got we got like the best
underwriters we've got you know deep
pockets financial pockets you know we've
got the experience you know we've got a
lot of data can we use these strengths
POC you know areas you know to convert
them into advantages you know in the
digital world you know that's really the
question which I would you know ask and
then of course you know I think you know
you already spoken about products and
ecosystem you know again how do we think
more from the customers mindset and we
need to design products you know which
the customer likes you know whether I
mean again travel insurance to my mind
as of is my favorite example overseas
medical insurance you know so while
every
the writer knows that probably 95% of
the lost claim ratios you know comes
from medical illness in an emergency
which happens outside India but if you
ask the customers I mean for the
customers the value of that is only 5%
and you know most of the customers you
know if you are able to help them in the
loss of a passport you know if they are
in a South American country or get the
Forex when their wallet gets stolen or
they lose their baggage that's of much
much more value so the customer I mean
finally you know we need to listen the
customer is you know right and we need
to listen to our customers if the
customer wants to consume and you know
their products you know his or her
products and their needs are different
you know so then we need to as an
industry you know we need to move this
thing again when I look at you know
historically probably you know when I
used to you know let's say use taxi as a
service so maybe you know every taxi you
know so do about you know 24 trips in a
year and maybe thousand rupees a week so
total cost was 2,400 rupees but today a
twenty four thousand rupees you know so
today when you look at it the same
consumption everybody concerned consumes
an uber or an Ola
but the trip cost has become 100 rupees
you know but the number of trips from 24
has you know maybe you know become you
know you know maybe a 200 or 300 trips
in the year so I think you know that's
the way you know we are looking so there
will be the ticket size of the products
you know will become much smaller and
the velocity you know though of
transaction you know so will become you
know much larger so if somebody needs a
high-end camera and shorts or one day
you know who am I to you know so
insurance and does he somebody will come
and meet that need
so his insurance industry if is one
company says you know that we are now we
it doesn't fit into our mindset you know
so I think the customer is always right
and we will need to you know move or to
that and the other thing is you know of
course you know there is lot of
ecosystem data which is available and
how can we use it intelligently to
design product to underwrite better
that's the other thought which I you
know want to leave with you so those are
you know few of the thoughts you know
which I had so but fundamentally I'll
again end with the thought which I
started I think you know it's the key is
to
and the customer mind set and be very
very open to change our own mindset you
know as an organization even if it means
destroying parts of something you know
which we have created ourselves thank
you ladies and gentlemen we have come to
the end of the first session I would now
request my colleagues to present the
dignitaries with a memento as a token of
gratitude
[Applause]
thank you sir
I would now request the Vishnu and
Himanshu to take over and commence the
second session thank you
ladies and gentlemen good afternoon let
us now begin with the second session of
even I am Himanshu
and I am the via the theme for this
session is succeeding in the era of
innovation this will be followed by a
Q&A session with immense pleasure we
would not like to introduce esteemed
dignitaries for this session mr. Amit
Nayak CEO and co-founder metamorphosis
technologies mr. Vijay Kumar CEO and
principal officer go digit may I may I
now request you both to please come up
on the stage and form the dice
we now request our colleagues to
formally welcome the panel with a floral
bouquet
we will be proceeding with the
presentation first up we have mr. Amit
Naik sir will be presenting on the topic
innovation through technology and ensure
tech perspective
but before that a brief introduction of
sir mr. Amit Naik CEO and co-founder of
metamorphosis technologies which is an
inshore tech brings with him an
experience of two decades in the
industry sir has a deep Insurance
expertise with focus on life health and
general insurance mr. Naik has a
specialization in various domains
including new account development sea
level client relationship analyst
relationship competitor analysis and
marketing I request her to kindly begin
with the presentation
good afternoon everybody I would like to
thank mr. Srinivasan and the entire ni
team for giving me this privilege to be
a part of this event and talk about
innovation through technology and in
short X perspective so when I was
thinking what I need to present I
realized that rather than going through
the data and statistics that's already
available on Google why don't we give a
perspective based on what we have been
interacting with various insurance
companies globally yeah and we have
talked a lot about inshore tech
connected ecosystems I'd certainly cover
a few of those in my presentation but
the key is we'll understand what is a
foundation that a insurance company
needs to have to be able to compete with
this new age digital insurers
so I wanted to start in the store shot
video
[Applause]
yeah so
so what do you saw in the video is it a
dream or reality if you look at it all
of us want such kind of an experience
and it is becoming an reality if you
look at the crop insurance home
insurance drones are at play and one of
the prospects we are working with they
are using the drone technology to do the
surveys and talking about the sensors
telematics you can know exact location
of that accident and of course a taxi
can be dispatched to you the towing
truck can come there but what is
stopping the current increment insurance
companies from achieving this so before
we talk about in short tag let's
actually define who and in short a case
and in short tech as there are multiple
ways to look at it Macon's he has a
definition for in short tag there are
other companies which are defined in
short a but our viewers and in short
tech is any technology vendor or the
partners and ecosystems who can enable
an existing insurance company to take
that leap and become a digital insurer
so if you look at this slide it's
confusing right there are so many
players in the market so when an
insurance company is evaluating some of
this technology vendors it's very very
difficult for them to evaluate what it
is how do we look at which are the
technologies they need to invest in and
we believe that there is a certain
process and method through which
insurance companies can evaluate what
technology is relevant to them and share
some of them today
yeah so I think before we go into the
technology part let's understand what
impact it has created on the industry so
if you look at it on the left side we
see that the maximum impact of in Shore
Tech has been on the PNC industry or the
general insurance industry followed by
the health within that the maximum
impact has been on the distribution side
now one of the reasons for this is that
most of this in short X have focused on
low ticket products they have focused on
epic episode ik insurance they have
focused on electronic items shipping
insurance which are much much easier to
sell and they have also focused on the
life side moon mainly on the pure risk
which is a term product and on the right
side if you see where has been the
maximum impact on the growth side they
have been able to really leverage and
cross-sell and upsell really well so
what is the reason for that because they
have had a better customer experience it
might be through a superior service it
could be a through a mobile-first
approach but they have had that leverage
and that's why they have been able to
cross-sell and upsell so we have seen
that in Shore Tech there are multiple
players and an insurer tech need not be
an insurance company which is taking a
risk in short and can be an technology
vendor who helps with the ecosystem and
partnerships to help an incubate
insurance company to become one of the
in short x
yeah so if you see the current landscape
we have the traditional insurers and
they have mainly focused on one product
fits all approach and the biggest
challenge they face to raise and we have
seen just now Malaysia was presenting he
talked about legacy policy admin
platforms the legacy infrastructure this
is one of the biggest hurdles for an
insurance company to take that next step
and compete with new ways digital
insurance companies but if you think of
it some of these companies have operated
for 40 50 80 years and they are fearful
of an inshore tech which has just come
from three years back or four years back
what is the reason they have so much of
customer data why can't they analyze
that and come out with certain products
there are multiple reasons for that you
know if you look at a traditional
insurance company and I can give some
examples from India and from outside one
of the insurance company we are
currently working with they have six
policy administration platforms and
Nilesh was talking about it takes it
should not take more than a week to
launch a product but some of these
companies are taking anywhere between
three to four months to launch a product
and when you are talking about the
partnership let's say you want to
partner with a Fitbit or a goki or car
IQ who are your ecosystem partners they
want the data or they want the product
to be available immediately they cannot
wait for three months six months period
that is one of the biggest challenges
insurance companies are facing whereas
if you look at a new-age company because
they have a mobile-first approach they
are already on a cloud platform and they
already have certain lean and
lightweight platforms available with
them so to compete with them what we
believe is in between this traditional
insurance companies and the new-age
digital companies there are a few in
short tech technology vendors who can
help you take that leap and that leap
can happen through something we known as
a foundation layer which I'll talk more
about the next slide but basically what
they're going to do is they're going to
help you to have a layer on top of this
policy administration platform so that
you can leverage the existing
investments that have been made people
have spent millions of dollars on this
policy administration's platform and the
when we analyze some of the data what we
realize is while this insurance
companies are in the business of risk
but they're really really fearful to
take a risk
with a start-up technology vendor that
is the reality of that
so without disturbing the current policy
admin platforms we feel that the
foundation layer can build an internal
ecosystem which then can interact with
an external ecosystem yeah and mainly
this ecosystem can tilt the balance in
the favor of an traditional company
because they have the biggest asset they
have the customer data and then they can
leverage some of these technologies to
do dynamic pricing and they can build a
connected ecosystem of partners so we
have heard a lot about artificial
intelligence and machine learning and of
course if you look at any business it's
certainly going to impact it and there
are huge implications and one side we
have people who have predicted gloom and
doom and other side people who feel that
a IML can completely transform a
business and we certainly believe that a
IML is going to transform and if you
don't invest in this technologies if you
don't innovate it's going to be very
tough for an insurance companies to
exist but before that what is that
foundation layer that I was talking
about
so this is the foundation layer and many
of you will be surprised that why would
an insurance company if is existed for
ten fifteen or thirty years need this
kind of an foundation layer let me give
some examples if you look at the first
one the product configurator we believe
this is the heart of any transformation
if you look at any partnership that's
going to happen whether it's with the
Wellness Center with the travel wisely
whether it's a telematics player or a
connected car system it's all going to
happen with your ability to do dynamic
pricing within your product and if you
are going to take four months or six
months or eight months to launch a
product it's not going to work out so
you need to invest and build a great
product configurator and there are many
technology vendors who are providing
this product so you can take off the
shelf product customize it to your needs
but that is the first step so let me
give an example if you take a simple
product like travel insurance there are
multiple benefits within that it could
be an hijack it could be trip delay it
could be a personal accident cover
within that and when we were talking to
one of the insurance companies they
wanted to break this benefits and allow
the customer to choose and create his
own product now this may sound very
simple and for this they wanted to tie
up with a lot of airline partners they
want to tie up with a few dealers and
the proposition that came out was it's
going to take them internally around
eight months to be able to come out with
this product when we when there we
presented and they implemented the
product configurator what we could do is
unbundle all the benefits and the
premium pricing and rate tables were
defined at a benefit level so for each
of this there was an rate table rather
than a common premium for all of these
benefits and whether it's the agent it's
a dealer it's a travel agent or the d2c
customer he is able to now choose pick
what he wants what's best for him and in
today's age of on-demand kind of
products wherein if I'm taking over our
uber
I want to just ensure myself for that
specific trip you want to need the
capability in the product configurator
to be able to have an on/off switch we
can help you with such product
innovation or it could be we are now
working with one of the insurance
companies for a personal accident probe
and these are actually low premium
products they want the capability that
if a person wants to switch it off for
four months you should be able to switch
it on so this is the kind of innovation
that's happening but it cannot happen
with a strong foundation layer and one
of them is the product configurator
certainly and if you look at it we
talked in the morning about a regulatory
sandbox if your product configurator
cannot let you define a product which is
for a certain segment which is for a
certain market which is for a certain
time period you are going to be in
trouble you can't you probably will have
there are 50 applications that can come
in but your ability to define that
product come out of the market is going
to take time also we have been talking
to some of the insurance companies
they're struggling with the regulatory
changes on benefit illustration because
there are certain commitments on a poor
person and 8% rate if these are the
things that you're spending time on
internally your IT team it's a challenge
because the new age digital insurer is
focused on the customer experience it's
going to beat your yeah so apart from
the product configurator and the rating
engine the second thing is a customer
acquisition I don't think we have talked
a lot about this more mobile-first
approach but what is the most important
thing here is a simplified process for
buying insurance if you're going to have
8 to 10 pages of form to be filled out
it's not going to work for this mobile
savvy the digital age insurance so we
need to have simple forms and this is
where this the third part the auto
underwriting engine which we have been
talking about since morning helps and
there are two aspects to it you know one
is underwriting that happens at an
individual level rather than a group
level so what we are talking is not on
the data that's actual data based on a
group but can i underwrite the case
based on the specific merits of that
particular individual so it could be
data from social media of course there
are regulatory challenges on that but
there is data available today and within
the insurance company there is enough
data available about that
customer we have seen that the same
customer is existing in five policy
administration platforms and some of the
insurance companies are not able to have
a unified customer view for it so that
this data itself is good enough for you
to able to underwrite and pricing of
course other things like if the case is
a complicated case it's never going to
be straight through process based on
completely on rules so if you look at a
case which is like 10 crore thumb plan
or its unit link plan it's going to
require manual underwriting but does the
underwriter have an underwriting
workbench which is giving him the power
to have a look at his existing quotation
claims the health data MIB data can this
be integrated with India stack which
gives you data on eky c platforms so
this is very very critical from
underwriting perspective and that's
where I think insurance companies need
to spend their money on an underwriting
workbench and finally it's the moment of
truth is when you are going to service
the customer when a claim comes in if
his experiences you're gonna make him
fill up lengthy forms the same questions
are going to be asked like what we saw
in the accident happened there is one
insurance company which is completely
digital they sent out a uber car to him
they sent out a talking truck and the
drone came and took the photographs and
the claim was auto logged whereas there
is someone who's struggling with IVR
system on the phone so I think claims is
a very very critical area and we believe
that again there needs to be an
underwriting workbench similar claims
workbench which gives the claims
adjudicated a complete view and what is
important is can the data that was
shared during the underwriting time be
available to the claim adjudicator
because this is a time he can analyze
whether there's a possibility of a fraud
that has happened
so how would this platform look like
right you build the foundation layer so
on the left you see there are multiple
distribution channel
there could be agents agencies there is
a D to C that is banker
we have affinity channels and of course
that there's a concept of a mall
insurance so if you look at it
all of these people whether it's the
agent or a customer affinity they expect
a completely omni-channel experience and
when we talk about omni-channel it has
to run across the distribution channels
and also from a technology perspective
he expects it to work on an iOS device
it works on an Android device he should
be able to go home on his laptop or a
Mac he should be able to access the same
data on a browser so the data has to
seamlessly flow from one platform to
another platform and once this
foundation layer is ready
like I said integrating this with a
policy admin system and ensuring that
the policy admins system just becomes a
place where all this records are stored
you know you don't need to replace a
policy admin platform the servicing the
endorsements can still happen there
because all the innovation that we have
seen is happening more on the product
pricing underwriting in claim side and
customer acquisition time so let that
investment that you are made and there
is a way to do this you could start with
simple products you can take personal
accident product travel product you can
take up a motor insurance product then
gradually if your life insurers move
first with term insurance product take
this whole thing as a proposition on the
cloud and try out the term products yeah
but the most important thing is the
ecosystem and I think my previous
presenter emulation was talking more
about this because very very critical
from a PNC perspective your ability to
connect with open API is on a
microservices architecture so apart from
the four traditional channels what we
have seen the bancassurance agents d2c
and affinity there are other players who
can help you sell we have seen there is
one of the insurers who is betting on a
hundred in asia-pacific a Japanese
insurer one hundred millions just
betting on the travel product again
if you can host this api's they are open
ApS available to your dealers to your
point of sale grenadiers to brokers it's
going to be much much much easier to
integrate and sell and we certainly
believe that this entire ecosystem
requires the foundation layer to be
there the open API is be there and then
you can partner with them so it could be
fitness devices
it could be wellness players so we all
heard of ping on which has the Chinese
insurer and we heard them today in the
morning where they have built a complete
ecosystem around this but if you look at
some of the examples in asia-pacific
discovery then AI of vitality they've
done an amazing job and ensuring this
ecosystem so they're tied up with gym
memberships the wellness the fitness
data how many calories you are burned
and the whole pricing and premium is
based on that data
similarly in India we have had
telematics providers who have
implemented the usage based insurance
and depending on the way you drive how
you drive the entire pricing is
happening but for all of this to happen
the most critical thing is that the
insurance company should be able to
expose and get this ApS out in the
market only then this is possible yeah
so I said a IML is certainly important
but we strongly feel YAML it's in itself
is a journey it can only happen when
this base foundation layer is in place
once this is in place so we are
investing a lot of money now on this AML
platform wherein based on the location
we are able to attack which agent should
contact whom then we are able to do the
underwriting price based on this there's
a lot of fraud analytics that we have
been able to do on the claims the fraud
propensity so it's certainly possible
but you need to ensure that the basic
foundation layer is absolutely ready
then of course the customer segmentation
cross-sell upsell the predictive
analytics fraud analytics you're
robo-advisor RPA all of this can come
into the platform
yeah so in the end you can accelerate
the journey it needs to start like what
I said with first identifying a good
inshore tech and the definition of
inshore tech like I said probably there
are two categories there are in short X
who are themselves taking a risk and are
underwriting the risk and then their
partner we partnering with insurance
companies but the challenge there is are
you ready to give out your data because
we have seen cases where some of this in
short X himself have later become
insurance companies so are you ready to
give out your data which is the main
thing which will help you compete with
the digital insurance companies second
thing is do you want to ensure that you
are giving out your most critical IT
systems out to this vendors or rather
you want to build internally so it's a
build versus buy approach but if there
is an inch or take a technology vendor
who is not owning your data his game is
not a valuation game but is willing to
partner with you to help you with the IP
and product culture I think that's the
right vendor for you once this is in
place of course what we discussed is the
three steps which is building and
foundation lever building and partner
ecosystem and finally applying the a ml
thing I think this is what I want to
share rather than the the data or
statistics that's already available so
I'm open for any questions you have
thank you sir for throwing light on the
new technological impact on the industry
for our next presentation I am honored
to introduce mr. Vijay Kumar who is the
CEO and principal officer of gorget who
will be presenting on the topic digital
breakthrough impact on the insurance
industry but before that a brief
introduction of sir throughout his
career of nearly two decades sir has
only worked with the startup companies
in the auto and insurance sector like
kirlosker tractors Maruti Suzuki
Hyundai and Gore digit sir had started
his career with the automobile industry
and later became a part of Bajaj Allianz
where Sir headed various functions
including motor OD claims motor
third-party claims and consumer legal
cases so requesting you to please begin
with the presentation
yes
good afternoon friends before I start I
would like to thank mr. Severson
director and ie the faculty members and
IA and all the youngsters sitting here
in the audience given the time 15
minutes I think I will like to be
restricted myself to you know so what
exactly on the Digital side has happened
in the industry and how they Nestle is
impacted so I think generally I find a
lot of criticism about the insurance
Indian general insurance industry that
you know that Nestle has not done
anything or not doing enough you know
for the customer or for itself so I am
bit positive and I want to start with
the positive on the positive note saying
that while globally I think a lot of
innovations happened the Indian general
insurance industry also has done a lot
and we are not very far from what others
are doing so the video which have it
showed just now I think some of the
examples we have in in in our industry
as well I know to catch up with all
those you know best practices know the
digital evolution obviously being part
of the global family in India I think
obviously has also changed significantly
and evolved on the digital front
so internet reaching every nook and
corner of the country I think 0.5
billion Internet users in India so we
have ample scope to change the insurance
an area the youngsters today are using
apps some of the you know some of them
up to 24 apps per day actually maybe all
our birth males etcetera so I think the
the internet enablers are there for us
to exploit so obviously in the insurance
cannot you know stay away from these
changes and the Indian insurance
industry also changing significantly
perhaps we have not reached the level of
you know the other technology companies
like Amazon or maybe Ola but because of
valid reasons there are good reasons
actually why we haven't I know reached
to that level but I won't say that it
was status is in any way we are less and
progressing well in that direction the
change in the industry actually if there
are little impediments the few reasons
because we are we have to carry the risk
which is a taken to into account all the
you know the risk perception in ever all
the processes and systems the cost of
investment in the technology side which
Amit mentioned just now I think he is
given a fair idea of you know how the
technology what kind of technology is
available and but it comes at a very
high cost and for any
pterence the margins are obviously
limited and and particularly for the new
companies like us who are startup
companies I think for them the investing
so huge amount towards technology I
think is a challenge the other reason I
would also like to cite here is the
regulatory